Satrunjaykumar

Mobile: +91-8010855125
Email: satrunjaykumar@gmail.com

INFORMATION SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR/NETWORK SERVICES ADMINISTRATOR /IT SUPPORT

IT Professional with Total 10 years of experience in System Administration, Networking and IT Infrastructure.

Technical Skills:

ERP

Microsoft Platform Planning, Implementing and Maintaining a Windows Server Network

Infrastructure & Environment 2000, 2003, 2008, 2012 Server.

Installing, Configuring, Active **directory DNS, DHCP** & **Group Policies**. Experienced On **IDS Fortune** Enterprise Property Management System

(Integrated Module for various department of Hotel.

Experienced on IDs Front office System, Point Of Sale, Back office Accounting

System.

Experienced on **EZEE Absolute** Property Management System, Point Of Sale, Material Management, Club Management System, Spa Management System

and Customer Relationship Management System, Human Resource Experienced on Various biometrics attendance Recording Software like

Savior, and Door lock Systems like **ONITY**.

Experienced on Guest complaint System (AT your Service)

Network and Telephone

Capable of Planning a Network setup, Including hardware Planning, cable laying plan, installation of switches and Routers, LAN/WAN /Wi-Fi infrastructure design and implementation. Through understanding of

networking concepts such as leased line, ISDN.

Experienced with **Zexel**, **Wijungle**, Knowledge of Hotel **Internet**

Gateway

Fair knowledge of Samsung, Siemens and Alcatel Telephone Epabx

<u>Antivirus</u> Experienced with Sugrite Endpoint, McAfee Antiviruses, Quick Heal

Total Security

Software Installation, Troubleshooting & Reconfigure Ms outlook 2007, 2013, 2016

Tally Erp, office 365 Home Edition, Pet Puja Restaurant Billing setup.

Educational and Other Qualifications:

■ **Education** Graduate in B. Com (HONS) from Nalanda Open University, Patna.

Professional Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP).

HUBNET Certification Course Hardware, MCSE, CCNA from Boring Road

Patna.

HTML.SQL & C++ in LaL Bahadur Shastri Institute from New Delhi.

Professional Experience

<u>Organization:-</u> Seasons Group Hotel, Catering, Resort & Restaurants.

Site: Seasons Catering Services Pvt. Ltd. (From Sept 2014 to Till Date 30th Aplril 2021)

Role: IT Executive

- Windows Server Administration
- ➤ Domain Server Active Directory installation, Management, Create user accounts, group policy & share folder permission.
- Configuration of AWS CLOUD, EC2 SETUP, FTP, Remote Desktop Service etc.
- ➤ Wi-Fi Internet Provisioning for int0ernal staff and customers
- ➤ Installation ,Configuration and maintenance of **WI JUNLE** firewall
- ➤ Managing &Monitoring station for Network switches and Routers (CISCO, DLINK)
- ➤ Installation, configuration and maintenance of **CCTV Camera and DVRS** in collaboration n with Security Department.
- Configuration and Backup of SQL Server 2008R2
- Management of Siemens Epabx with 64 extensions
- ➤ Taking Care Of Software License renewals
- Website Manage with update photo, function achievement award with deign upload in Social Media.
- Manage G-suit Email sever 100 users, E mail Creation & Troubleshooting.

Organization:- Grenville Hotels Pvt.Ltd. (29 November 2013 to May 2014)

Site: Asst. IT Executive Role: Manager (IT &EDP)

- ➤ Looking after the Entire IT & Telecom Setup Of the Company
- Windows Server 2008R2 Server Management
- > Active Directory Management
- > IT Asset Management and Procurement of New Materials related to IT and Telecom
- ➤ Negotiation & finalization of **AMC** with venders, ensuring proper service obtained From all the vendors as and when required.
- ➤ Installation, configuration and maintenance of **CCTV Camera and DVRS** in collaboration n with Security Department.
- > Remote and Onsite IT Support to various Branches of Company in Delhi and Gurgaon.
- ➤ Configuration and Backup of **SQL Server 2008R2 and ERP (WINHMS)**
- ➤ Planning and Implementing the End User Training to New Team Members of other Departments.
- Configure Zyxel firewall, Zyxel Access point, billing machine.
- Maintain vingCard door lock & locker.
- Manage Biometric Machine (Adman Technologies).

Organization: - IT Support 4U (March 2013 to Sept 2013)

Site: Hotel Altis by Aveda, kirti Nagar Sect-15 Gurgaon. / Corporate office, Pitampura, Delhi,

Role: IT Executive

- ➤ Manage IBM Sever X3500 M2
- ➤ Hotel Software using IDS Fortune Express V4.139 and creating user, delegate permission in all department.
- Onity door access manage and create user to access door from shift wise & floor wise.
- Everyday Report on send all report work on day in head office through mail.
- Creating and Maintaining Active directory and Group Policies
- Asset and software Inventory management, software license Management.
- ➤ Installation, Configuration and Management Of IDS Software ERP, CCTV and EPABAX
- Installation and Maintenance of Audio Visual equipment's

Organization: - Robosapiens Technology Pvt. Ltd. Noida (Oct 2011 to March 2013)

Site: Robosapiens Technology

Role: Network Engineer

- > Providing remotely support or telephonic on more than 50 Windows and Mac client.
- Troubleshooting Break Fix issues related to OS performance, Network issues, Ping failure, DHCP, IP, FTP,NIC, Print servers, Driver, Free Disk Space, Patch Installation issues, MS-Outlook.
- ➤ Installing and Monitoring and repair CCTV Camera.
- > Troubleshooting Hardware and Operating system related issue.
- ➤ Installing, Configuring, Maintaining MATRIX EPABX.
- ➤ Hp, Dell and Acer laptop repair, hardware component change.
- Installation, End User training on various client sites in north India.
- Providing remote and Onsite support to clients in terms of smooth operation of software's application

Organization: **Donear Industry Pvt. Ltd.** (sept 2010 to Aug 2011)

Site: D'COT Ltd deputed at Chandiwali Mumbai

Role: **IT Support**

- ➤ Managing Windows Sever 2003 Domain Environment of more than 200 Workstations & Servers in Windows 2003 Domain Environment.
- ➤ Managing (Creation / Sharing of folders & assign them appropriate permissions)
- > OS installation, troubleshooting on all the Hp Dell.
- Managing MCAFEE EPO 4.5 Antivirus, on server as well as client end.
- Providing proactive support in managing a LAN/WAN Network, Desktop management.
- ➤ Installation of telephone software Aspect amp software(calling facility provide)
- > Tech support for Wizapp application.
- > Remote installation on Wizapp application & training provide from the Gallery (showroom).
- ➤ Showroom Auditing across the billing Management software
- ➤ Ensuring the smooth functioning of all critical Front Office and Back office Applications by maintaining the High Systems Uptime with the help of Consistent and scheduled Preventive Maintenance of Software and Hardware.
- ➤ Ensuring the Maximum Internal Customer satisfaction.
- ➤ Responsible for managing the **LAN** and the **WIFI** networks

Personal Details:

Father Name	: Upendra Prasad Singh
Date of Birth	: 18-02-1989
Marital Status	: Unmarried
Permanent Address	: Prakash Sadan Near Animal hospital, Shyam Nagar, Jehanabad, Bihar.
Correspondence Addr	ress: K.H.No.80/10 Gali no4, Vashist Enclave, Burari Delhi-84.
Date:	
Place:	(Satrunjay kumar)